kaki narase sonzai wo
rock away your existence
koko ni iru to
shouting that you are here
arata na tabi ga ima hajimaru
a new journey begins now
kawari yuku kisetsu no naka wo ikinuku tabi ni bokura
as we survived through the changing seasons
chie to tsuyosa wo te ni ireta kedo JUST LOOKS LIKE SURVIVAL GAME
we gained knowledge and strength (just looks like a survival game)
nagareteku jikan no naka ni
but the forgotten memories
okizari ni shita omoi wo
of the feelings abandoned within the flows of time
wasureta koto sura wasurete ita
have also been lost
kuzure kaketa toki kodoku wo shitte
when sinking down we learned loneliness
deaeta bokura hitori ja nai
but now we've met each other we are no longer alone
sarake dase kanjou wo banjou no omoi wo
unveil your feelings those high emotions
namidame ga unmei wo kaete yuku
those tears will change your fate
yami ni uchi narase kodou wo
pound your heartbeat against the darkness
kitto aeru yo onaji itami no hata no moto de
we're sure to meet under the same flag of pain
Wow. There's a lot of new houses
being built around here.
I hear it's been a bit
of a construction boom recently.
Seems like a lot of the construction sites
are short-handed
and they're hiring carpenters
from outside of the country, too.
Even I know that.
Oh, Old Man Genno!
Naruto.
Who is he?
He's a carpenter from the Land of Sand.
He likes ramen, and we bump
into each other at Ichiraku.
How about we go there after this?
Yeah!
Here you go, thanks for waiting!
Thank you for this meal!
Thank you.
Ichiraku's ramen is the best, after all!
Isn't it so? Isn't it so?
I'm sorry, but can I have some water?
Sure!
— Thank you for this meal!
— That was fast!
Are you full already?
No... Not really.
Then I'll give you mine.
Lucky!
Hey, Naruto!
The two of them are always like this.
They act as if they're really grandfather
and grandson.
Oh, come on, Sakura,
stop being so harsh.
There are lots of other people
who complain. Like Grandma Tsunade.
And there's Shino, Ino, Kiba,
and Kakashi-sensei...
But I guess you're the harshest, Sakura.
Come on, Naruto!
That's only
because you're always at fault!
Now, now, Sakura calm down.
You hair will turn grey... Ouch!
Looks like it's time I got to business.
— Hey, hey.
— Help me, Old Man Genno!
A Tough Pinch!
The Hidden Leaf 11 All Gather
Damn!
What is it? Fog?
Well, I guess it doesn't matter.
Tsunade-sama.
I'm sorry to bother you
during your sleep,
but the man that the ANBU Black Ops
had marked...
Has made his move?
He is currently on the run.
On the run?
Are you telling me even
with the array of the ANBU Black Ops,
we still can't catch him?
Who is he?
You must know his identity by now.
There was nobody
in the recent Bingo Book
that fit his description,
but when we checked
an older Bingo Book...
Genno?
Genno the Trapper?
You know of him?
He should be quite old by now.
I hadn't heard his name in a while,
so I thought
that he had already retired, but...
I never would have thought
that he was infiltrating the Leaf Village.
I guess I can't fight against old age.
No. I guess I should say this is just
what I expect of the Leaf ANBU Black Ops.
We want you to hand over the thing you
took from the master carpenter's house.
You think I would still be holding
onto that thing?
I've had a long life as a Shinobi.
I guess it wouldn't be so bad
to close the curtain at this time.
Though I regret
that I won't be able to see
the end of the Leaf Village
with my own eyes!
Paper Bombs!
Retreat!
Are you saying that someone
is planning a huge attack
against the Leaf Village?!
That would be the only reason
anyone would want those plans,
aside from carpentry purposes.
Genno's last words suggest that as well.
It's going to take some time
to decipher those plans,
but it's too dangerous to depend on that.
The enemy may attack us
at any minute.
Activate the S-Level Emergency
Security Alert!
Leave the least amount
of men necessary here,
and all other men are to secure
the border!
Attack anyone who tries to cross
Don't allow them to attack the village,
no matter what!
Such great weather!
Naruto!
Oh! Sakura!
That sounds like a big pain in the ass.
I think you'll be able to do it.
That is why we left you in the village.
At the very least, is there any way
that we can get more people?
Under these circumstances,
we can't turn over more people to you.
They're the greatest lineup for you,
aren't they?
The greatest, huh?
Fog? Last night's weather didn't seem
like it was going to be foggy.
How strange.....
Was it all a dream?
Doesn't it seem like
we're really low on people?
That's what I was thinking, too.
From the looks of it,
the village must be
under special security alert.
What?! For real?!
I didn't notice it!
You should notice these kinds of things.
You're a Ninja.
But if we're in a state of emergency,
it's a huge deal for the village,
isn't it?
Why haven't they told us anything?
That's why Tsunade-sama is calling us.
Come in.
Tsunade-sama, I brought Naruto.
Shikamaru.
So, you must have been left out, too.
What are you taking about?
Nothing.
Oh, hey, Shikamaru.
About last night's weird fog...
Did you see it?
Stop it. You were just dreaming.
There was no fog.
See. I told you.
That was a smoke screen.
Smoke screen?
I'll explain once everyone gets here.
Naruto, Sakura...
The reason why we left you out
of the S-Level Emergency
Security Alert unit
is because we wanted you
to work under Shikamaru
for a special mission.
— What?
— Well, that's the case.
First, I want you to gather
the people I'm about to name.
Hey, calm down, Naruto!
But it's already past the time
we were supposed to gather!
Not quite. To be accurate,
we still have 20 more seconds.
Seems like he's here.
Oh? Everyone's already here?
No matter how you look at it,
you're the last one!
Everyone's here now. Let's begin.
I'm sure
that you all have already noticed.
The village is currently under
the S-Level Emergency Security Alert.
It all started when...
The smoke screen last night, right?
— You guys noticed it?
— Of course.
The bugs were being noisy.
Huh? I didn't notice it.
You're always so out of it!
I didn't notice it either.
{"SAME LEVEL AS CHOJI!
WORSE THAN NARUTO!"
Could it be that I'm worse than Naruto?
"WORSE THAN NARUTO"
Worse than Naruto...
Worse than Naruto... Worse than Naruto...
So, what was that?
It seemed like something
involving the ANBU Black Ops.
So, I stayed put.
Yeah, that's correct.
The ANBU Black Ops were involved.
Just as I thought.
It was late last night.
A man that the ANBU Black Ops had
been marking for the past two weeks
had snuck into the home
of Leaf Village's top carpentry boss.
And he stole the plans of our village's
important facilities from the secret safe.
Plans...?
So, what's so bad about that?
He just stole the plans
for the facilities, right?
Just stole? You're so...
Naruto...
For example, let's say the plans
for the fort that surrounds the village
fell into enemy hands...
By analyzing those plans in detail,
the enemy could figure out
the most efficient way
to break into the village.
Now let's say that there were plans
for Tsunade-sama's mansion.
If you were to examine those plans,
you could find out how to get
into Tsunade-sama's room.
And if the plans were to get
into the hands of an assassin...
That's really, really bad.
Last night's smoke screen was...
something that suspect spread
as he was running away.
I see.
In the end, ANBU Black Ops cornered him
in the Western Forest.
He killed himself
before they could get him to talk.
Unfortunately,
when he committed suicide,
he wasn't in possession of the plans
he had stolen.
If the plans have already fallen
into the hands of the enemy,
it'd be a re-enactment of the nightmare
of the Destruction of Leaf Village.
In order to prevent that from happening,
the S-Level Emergency Security Alert
was deployed this morning.
So, what is the mission
for those of us left behind?
Find out the location of the stolen plans
and bring them back.
That's our mission.
It's like finding a needle in a haystack.
We just need to investigate
the path he took
and people he was acquainted with.
It turns out that the guy was famous
for being a top-level trap technician.
It's a huge possibility
that he left traps where the plans are.
It's definitely plausible.
I understand.
We'll follow your instructions.
I'll do it.
Then let's start the investigation.
Turns out that the man had snuck
into the village
a few months ago
and worked as a carpenter.
This guy...
His name is... Genno.
You're kidding me.
There's no way! Old Man Genno loved
the ramen at Ichiraku!
He would never do anything that would
destroy the Hidden Leaf Village!
Listen, there's no way that a guy
who's sneaking in to an enemy village
would show his bad side.
He played the part of a good guy
to let people's guard down.
There is no way that anyone
who loves ramen could be a bad person!
No. That's not true Naruto.
Choji, you tell him.
Knock some sense into this guy.
Anyone who loves Ichiraku's ramen
can't be a bad person!
Choji!
Gosh, I can't depend on anybody.
This is a list of the stolen plans.
I'm so embarrassed
we lost our important plans.
I can't show my face to Tsunade-sama.
Which construction jobs
were Genno involved with?
None of them.
But wasn't he working under you?
I don't allow outsiders to work
on any construction
that involves the safety of the village.
That old man only worked
on residential construction.
Which means...
there's little possibility that he snuck
some traps into the construction.
I think it's impossible.
We should check everything,
just in case.
I'm counting on you.
Lady Hinata, please take care of these.
Yes!
— I'll go, too.
— Me, too.
I mentioned it earlier,
but there is a possibility
that the plans haven't fallen
into the enemy's hands yet.
It's possible that he could have hidden it
while he was running away.
And it's our mission to find that.
Understood.
It's the start of a treasure hunt.
I'm depending on you, Akamaru.
Go!
Ino and Sakura, you guys go check
the old man's body.
There might be some clues.
What?! Us?
I got it.
All right! You just want me to go, right?!
I'll go!
Sakura, are you really okay with this?
I have to be. I'm training
to become a Medical Ninja.
I can't be afraid of something like this.
That might be the case for you, but...
Now... master carpenter.
Can you tell us everything you know
about Old Man Genno?
The old man came to Leaf Village
about three months ago.
He came to my place
with a recommendation letter
from a famous master carpenter
from the Land of Sand.
As you may already know,
there's a bit of a construction boom
in Leaf Village.
Every place is in need of more people.
And we needed more hands ourselves,
so we decided to hire him right away.
His carpeting skills...
were all right, just average.
I didn't feel the urge
to hire him permanently,
nor did I feel like I wanted
to fire him right away.
He took his job seriously.
He was perfect to hire
when we were short on people.
But after a while,
I found out that the recommendation letter
he brought was a fake.
This is the recommendation letter
he brought.
And how is this a fake?
There was a guy who brought
a recommendation letter
from the same master carpenter
more than ten years ago.
I just happened to find
that recommendation letter,
so I compared it and I noticed
that the handwriting was different.
And that recommendation letter?
It's over there in that cabinet.
Oh? Where did I put it?
I know I put it here.
It's okay if you don't have it.
I'm sorry.
For us, we really didn't care
if his recommendation letter was a fake
as long as he didn't do anything bad.
I just thought that I should let things
like this be known to Tsunade-sama.
I didn't think
that the old man was
a Shinobi from another country
and that he would steal our plans.
I still can't believe it.
Hey, is it really
that old man's doing?
I can't believe it either.
There are no signs of traps.
All right.
This is where the old man lived, huh?
He always paid the rent on time.
He really was quite proper.
Once in a while he'd come home
after drinking with his carpenter friends,
but he would never cause trouble.
Well, I did predict it,
but there are no clues.
— I found it!
— What did you find?
A special bonito broth, refreshing udon
and light broth super thin udon!
We're not looking for food!
But, usually,
if somebody is living by himself,
he'd probably stock up
on a bit more food.
There's only instant-cup udon.
Didn't he eat out a lot?
I hear that he went to Ichiraku a lot.
Right, Naruto?
Yeah.
If he cooked himself, he could have
eaten more and saved money.
Choji, we're not talking about you.
That old man barely talked about himself.
Just as I expected.
But he did happily talk about
how he became friends
with one of the kids in the village.
He might have heard something
from the old man.
Oh, I wonder about that.
What do you mean,
you wonder about that?
We won't know until we find the kid
and question him, won't we?
But it seems like there's no need for us
to look for him or question him.
What?! Then where is this guy!
Idiot, that kid is you, Naruto!
What?! Me?!
Yeah, there's no mistake about that.
You're Uzumaki Naruto?
We want to talk to you for a bit.
hoshikuzu suchasucha sucha odoru
on a checkerboard night
ichimatsu no yoru ni
when the stardust's are rapidly dancing
aa mada kaeri takunai to kuchi ni wa dasenai naa
I just can't come out and say, "ah, I don't want to go home yet"
omowa seburi terii
suggestively
aisubeki kao ni tsuba wo misutaa kuriketto
spat at that beloved face, mister cricket
asekusai suteeji no ue de hikaru toronboon no
the trombone gradually going off-key
picchi ga dandan hazureteitteiru no mo kininaru kedo
while on the sweaty center stage does bug me
sonna koto yori kono nai mune no moyamoya wa sakki
but more importantly, the fuzziness I feel in my undeveloped chest,
nonda koora no sei kashira nee
I wonder If it's from that coke I just drank?
I wonder what kind of interrogation
Naruto is undergoing?
I guess they would use
Regressive Hypnosis or something.
What's Regressive Hypnosis?
It's a Jutsu to draw out
subconscious memories.
Then Naruto might know something
even with his bad memory.
Hmm. I wonder about that.
Well, this Old Man Genno sounds
like he was pretty tricky...
Walt, why are you here anyway?
Next time:
"Even the Anbu Give Up. Naruto's Memory."